# NARDIN LACHOWSKI

# Software Engineer

203-570-9066 nardin.lachowski@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/nardinl nard1n.github.io Hingham, MA 02043

### SUMMARY

Results oriented web developer with over 5 years of experience in product integrations and software implementation projects. Have worked at fast-paced internet and software companies where I developed strong organizational skills leading all phases of diverse technology initiatives. Recently earned my **certificate** as a **full stack software engineer** and I am eager to apply my knowledge to continue making a lasting impact in the industry.

#### PROJECTS

## Takeoff | takeoff123.herokuapp.com | www.github.com/nard1n/takeoff

- Travel planning and blog application. Gives users ability to create itineraries of upcoming trips, add future trips to bucket list, and keep a blog of their favorite travel memories in one place without the clutter.
- Employed Passport.js middleware with Jsonwebtokens(jwt) to promote simple user login experience with a secure login
- Used React/Redux architecture to minimize complexity and maintain a consistent code layout from developer to developer while still keeping in mind further scalability.
- Technologies: JavaScript, CSS, NodeJS, Express, React, Redux, MongoDB, Miro, MailChimp, Deployed to Heroku

# Hulu Clone | hulu-clone-beta-woad.vercel.app | www.github.com/nard1n/hulu-clone

- · Mobile-first responsive Hulu.com clone. Using The Movie Database API to deliver movie data
- The site uses Next.JS for optimization purposes such as lazy loading in the viewport, and automatic image optimization
- Technologies: React.js, Next.js, TailwindCSS, Git, Deployed to Vercel

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# React Developer, Internship

Known Point Technologies

04/2021 - Present

Remote, MA

- · Uses React/Redux flux architecture to minimize complexity and maintain a consistent code layout
- Handles dynamic routing with React Router, increasing page-loading performance in a single-page environment to create a cohesive user experience while displaying multiple client views
- · Meets with development team to discuss user interface ideas and plans for development prioritization

### Implementations Technology Consultant

Paytronix Systems

10/2019 - Present Remote, MA

- Leads multifaceted client deployment of Enterprise and SMB clients as the sole project manager and technical consultant. Working to mitigate risks and decrease time between signing and launch
- Launched over \$30,000 in monthly recurring revenue annually in FY 2020
- · Learned the online ordering platform to help rapid restaurant implementation efforts during early COVID months
- Migrates demographic and financial data from previous providers to ensure financial accuracy and a seamless end user experience during a brand's transition between vendors

# Client Integrations Engineer

CJ Affiliate

12/2018 - 10/2019 Westborough, MA

- · Partnered with global advertiser brands across all verticals to deploy robust e-commerce tracking solutions
- · Provided solutions to optimize and streamline the utilization of Google Tag Manager (GTM) and Shopify API
- Implemented automated dashboards for integration deployment tracking serving cross-functional visibility and saving the integrations team over 20 hours each month
- · Monitored API performance and log management dashboards in Kibana/ ELK Stack for online web traffic

### Product Support Analyst

04/2015 - 12/2018

Indeed.com Stamford, CT

- · Utilized SQL to thoroughly analyze common trends in order to determine behavior and impact on end users
- · Extensive knowledge of third party and ATS integrations to ensure job requisitions render properly
- · Worked directly with Head of EMEA market on early GDPR risk assessments and privacy optimization initiatives
- Automated Client Satisfaction and Peer-to-Peer feedback programs with custom algorithms and Google Apps Script. Later, collaborated with Program Manager to integrate form into site to enhance performance and security

### EDUCATION

Full Stack Development Certificate, University of Connecticut, School of Engineering Bachelor of Science, Biological Sciences, University of Connecticut

20212013

# TECHNICAL SKILLS:

### Programming languages:

JavaScript, React.js, Python, Node.js

### Web Development:

HTML, CSS, jQuery, Redux, Express.js, Bootstrap, Materialize, Material UI

### Database and Analytics:

SQL, MongoDB, MySQL, JSON, AJAX, RESTful APIs, XML, Google Tag Manager

### Tools and Technologies:

Heroku, Git, ELK Stack, Miro, JIRA, Confluence, Salesforce, Zendesk, Smartsheets, ELK Stack, User Auth

### Additional Skills:

Deployment | Project Management | Employee onboarding and mentoring | Agile methodology | Cross-functional Collaboration | Customer Service | Product Research